Harry F. Brown Papers
© 2003 University of Connecticut
- Series V: 35mm Mounted Slides, consisting primarily of scenes along the electrified single-track Danbury Branch, and views of catenary modifications and other construction at New Rochelle Junction in connection with the Interstate 95 highway overpass construction, n.d., 1959, 1964
  - Subseries A: Black & White, n.d.
    - Catenary above a railroad track in a wooded area,n.d. (Box 8:228)
    - Catenary above a railroad track in a wooded area,n.d. (Box 8:229)
    - Two men standing in a road that crosses a railroad track,n.d. (Box 8:230)
    - Catenary over a railroad track in a wooded area,n.d. (Box 8:231)
    - Railroad tracks crossing a small railroad bridge with catenary above,n.d. (Box 8:232)
    - Railroad tracks with catenary above running near a group of industrial buildings in a rural area,n.d. (Box 8:233)
    - Two railroad tracks converging with catenary above. A sign on the bottom of an electrical pole to the right of the track reads "W",n.d. (Box 8:234)
    - View of catenary inside tunnel at Wall Street in South Norwalk, Connecticut, n.d. (Box 8:235)
    - View of catenary inside tunnel at Wall Street in South Norwalk, Connecticut, n.d. (Box 8:236)
    - View of New Haven Railroad 44-Ton diesel switcher with freight cars in industrial area north of Dock Yard, along Norwalk River in South Norwalk, Connecticut, n.d. (Box 8:237)
    - View in industrial area along the Norwalk River north of Dock Yard in South Norwalk, Connecticut, n.d. (Box 8:238)
    - View in industrial area along the Norwalk River north of Dock Yard in South Norwalk, Connecticut, n.d. (Box 8:239)
    - View in industrial area along the Norwalk River north of Dock Yard in South Norwalk, Connecticut, n.d. (Box 8:240)
    - View of interlocking tower SS44 at South Norwalk, Connecticut, n.d. (Box 8:241)
    - View of South Norwalk, Connecticut, passenger station, n.d. (Box 8:242)
    - A railroad track with catenary above in a wooded area,n.d. (Box 8:243)
    - A railroad track with catenary above in a wooded area,n.d. (Box 8:244)
    - A man walking into a field with Sperry Rail Service car 126 standing behind him. The field is in front of a large industrial building,n.d. (Box 8:245)
    - Catenary wires above two railroad tracks splitting in two with a large industrial building at the end of one track,n.d. (Box 8:246)
    - A passenger train at the platform of a railroad station with four triangular catenaries above,n.d. (Box 8:247)
    - Two New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad passenger trains at a railroad station with five traingular catenaries above,n.d. (Box 8:248)
    - New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad passenger train, with car 4228 in focus, with its pantograph raised at a railroad station. Above are four triangular catenaries,n.d. (Box 8:249)
    - Four triangular catenaries above a railroad station with a multiple unit train at the platform and a group of people waiting on the platform,n.d. (Box 8:250)
    - New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit passenger train, with five cars in view, on a railroad track with its pantograph in contact with the catenary wires,n.d. (Box 8:251)
    - A view of a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit passenger train of six cars on a railroad track with its pantograph in contact with catenary wires,n.d. (Box 8:252)
    - Another view of six cars on a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit passenger train with its pantograph in contact with catenary wires,n.d. (Box 8:253)
    - A close-up view of the connecting equipment in the gap between two multiple unit railroad cars,n.d. (Box 8:254)
    - The equipment under a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit car,n.d. (Box 8:255)
    - A close-up view of the pantograph on a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit passenger train in contact with catenary wires above,n.d. (Box 8:256)
    - Three cars of a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit passenger train with car 4402 in focus,n.d. (Box 8:257)
    - The door of multiple unit passenger car 4400 with its pantograph in view,n.d. (Box 8:258)
    - A street-level view of three cars of a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit passenger train on a railroad bridge above,n.d. (Box 8:259)
    - Another street level view of four cars on a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit train on a bridge above,n.d. (Box 8:260)
    - A train conductor inside a locomotive,n.d. (Box 8:261)
    - A conductor and a well-dressed man in a locomotive,n.d. (Box 8:262)
    - A conductor and a well-dressed man inside a locomotive,n.d. (Box 8:263)
    - A view from inside of a train locomotive approaching a large station in an unidentified city,n.d. (Box 8:264)
    - A view of two cars of a passenger train and catenary wires at a railroad station on a rainy day. Two men are visible on the platform,n.d. (Box 8:265)
    - Another view of a passenger train and catenary wires at a railroad station on a rainy day. Two men are on the platform in the distance,n.d. (Box 8:266)
    - A view of a stationary passenger train, an approaching train, and catenary wires at a railroad station on a rainy day. One man is on the platform in the distance,n.d. (Box 8:267)
    - A view of a train station with four triangular catenary above the tracks,n.d. (Box 8:268)
    - A bridge over a railroad track with catenary over the tracks,n.d. (Box 8:269)
    - A view of the entrance to a train station with four triangular catenary over the tracks leading into the station,n.d. (Box 8:270)
    - A view of a railroad track leading around a curve with triangular catenary above and an anchor bridge crossing the track,n.d. (Box 8:271)
    - A view of railroad tracks emenating out from under a bridge with catenary stretching away from the bridge,n.d. (Box 8:272)
    - A railroad track rounding a curve with an anchor bridge in close view and triangular catenary overhead,n.d. (Box 8:273)
    - Railroad tracks with a bridge crossing over them. A close-up view of an anchor bridge with catenary connected to it and following the tracks under the bridge ahead,n.d. (Box 8:274)
    - An anchor bridge over railroad tracks with catenary stretching out over the tracks and under a bridge ahead,n.d. (Box 8:275)
    - Railroad tracks rounding a curve with an anchor bridge crossing the tracks and catenary following the tracks under a bridge ahead,n.d. (Box 8:276)
    - A close-up view of triangular catenary stretching under a bridge that crosses the tracks,n.d. (Box 8:277)
    - Four railroad tracks with four triangular catenary following above. On the far left track is older locomotive 356 with at least one passenger car behind it,n.d. (Box 8:278)
    - Four railroad tracks rounding a curve with an anchor bridge crossing the tracks. Four triangular catenary follow the curve of the track above,n.d. (Box 8:279)
    - [Note: Images 280 through 338 are various scenes of a station, catenary structures, a wire train, new foundations, and other construction in the vicinity of New Rochelle Junction, all in connection with the Interstate 95 highway overpass construction.]
    - A view of converging railroad tracks with a signal tower to their left. Several anchor bridges are in view, one of which is holding transfomers. Catenary run above the tracks along the anchor bridges,n.d. (Box 8:280)
    - A closer view of a signal tower next to railroad tracks. Several anchor bridges are crossing the tracks, one of which holds several transformers. Catenary are running above the tracks,n.d. (Box 8:281)
    - A view of anchor bridge 65 on the Main Line looking east near New Rochelle, New York. The anchor bridge stands in front of a bridge that crosses the tracks. Catenary run under the bridge,n.d. (Box 8:282)
    - A view of anchor bridge 63 on the Main Line looking west in New Rochelle, New York. A signal tower stands to the left of the railroad tracks and the catenary are in clear view above the tracks,n.d. (Box 8:283)
    - The north post of anchor bridge 63 on the Main Line looking west in New Rochelle, New York with catenary in view,n.d. (Box 8:284)
    - Anchor bridge 62 on the Main Line in New Rochelle, New York looking west at the junction of the Main Line and the Harlem River Branch,n.d. (Box 8:285)
    - Anchor bridge 64 on the Main Line looking east in New Rochelle, New York with a clear view of the catenary following along the tracks,n.d. (Box 8:286)
    - The truss of anchor bridge 62 looking west at the track junction of the Main Line and the Harlem River Branch in New Rochelle, New York. A train approaches on the right side of the junction,n.d. (Box 8:287)
    - New Rochelle Junction, New York with a view of anchor bridge 61 on the Main Line and 211H on the Harlem River Branch. A train approaches on the right side of the junction,n.d. (Box 8:288)
    - Anchor bridge 63 in New Rochelle, New York looking east. Signal station 22 stands to the right of the track, n.d. (Box 8:289)
    - The south post of anchor bridge 62 looking east in New Rochelle, New York. A signal station stands to the right of the tracks,n.d. (Box 8:290)
    - The north post of anchor bridge 62 looking east in New Rochelle, New York. The image includes the converging tracks from the junction of the Harlem River Branch and the Main Line,n.d. (Box 8:291)
    - A westward view of New Rochelle Junction, New York showing anchor bridge 211H on the Harlem River Branch converging with anchor bridge 61 on the Main Line,n.d. (Box 8:292)
    - A westward view of anchor bridge 60 in New Rochelle, New York with a locomotive moving west on the right track,n.d. (Box 8:293)
    - A westward view of the south post of anchor bridge 60 in New Rochelle, New York. The south side of the tracks is under construction,n.d. (Box 8:294)
    - Anchor bridge 59 looking west in New Rochelle, New York. Triangular catenary wires follow above the tracks,n.d. (Box 8:295)
    - Anchor bridge 60 looking east at an oncoming locomotive in New Rochelle, New York ,n.d. (Box 8:296)
    - Looking east along the construction of a thruway west of Webster Avenue in New Rochelle, New York. The image is taken from farther back and includes several anchor bridges and some construction in front of them,n.d. (Box 8:297)
    - Another view looking east along the construction of a thruway west of Webster Avenue in New Rochelle, New York. This image includes several anchor bridges and construction in front of the tracks,n.d. (Box 8:298)
    - Looking west along the construction of a thruway west of Webster Avenue in New Rochelle, New York. Two men stand in an open area between construction materials and the railroad tracks,n.d. (Box 8:299)
    - Unfinished thruway bridge piers on the east side of Webster Avenue, New Rochelle, New York,n.d. (Box 8:300)
    - The north post of anchor bridge 210H on the Harlem River Branch in New Rochelle Junction, New York, with Main Line anchor bridges 60 and 61 in the background,n.d. (Box 8:301)
    - Anchor bridge 211H on the Harlem River Branch in New Rochelle Junction, New York, looking east. Transfomers line the top of the anchor bridge and a train passes on the Main Line side of the junction,n.d. (Box 8:302)
    - Looking east at New Rochelle Junction, New York, with a view of anchor bridge 61 on the Main Line and 211H on the Harlem River Branch,n.d. (Box 8:303)
    - Anchor bridge 62 looking east in New Rochelle, New York, with a view of signal station 22,n.d. (Box 8:304)
    - New Rochelle Junction, New York, looking east, including anchor bridge 62 and the Harlem River Branch west bound lead,n.d. (Box 8:305)
    - Footing for the thruway bridge pier in New Rochelle Junction, New York, including the north post of anchor bridge 61 on the Main Line,n.d. (Box 8:306)
    - North post of anchor bridge 61 on the Main Line looking east in New Rochelle Junction, New York. The construction of the thruway bridge is visible behind the anchor bridge on the left,n.d. (Box 8:307)
    - The north post of anchor bridge 60 in New Rochelle, New York, looking east. A train stands below the anchor bridge with a scaffold built on it to allow three men to work on the bridge,n.d. (Box 8:308)
    - The north post of anchor bridge 60 looking east in New Rochelle, New York. A New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad train, including car W934, stands below the bridge with a scaffold built on it, allowing three men to work on the bridge,n.d. (Box 8:309)
    - The south post of anchor bridge 60 looking east in New Rochelle, New York. Three workmen use the scaffolding built on a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad train, including car W934,n.d. (Box 8:310)
    - Anchor bridge 60 looking toward the north post in New Rochelle, New York, including a closer view of three workmen on the bridge,n.d. (Box 8:311)
    - The south post of anchor bridge 61 on the Main Line and the north post of anchor bridge 211H on the Harlem River Branch looking east and up in New Rochelle Junction, New York,n.d. (Box 8:312)
    - New Rochelle Junction, New York looking east at anchor bridge 62 on the Main Line,n.d. (Box 8:313)
    - Looking west along the Harlem River Branch under anchor bridge 211H, with anchor bridge 210H in the distance at New Rochelle Junction, New York,n.d. (Box 8:314)
    - New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad multiple unit car passenger train under anchor bridge 63 in New Rochelle Junction, New York looking east. The pantograph on the end of the train is visible,n.d. (Box 8:315)
    - Signal station 22 next to S16.SWHS,n.d. (Box 8:316)
    - Signal transfer at New Rochelle Junction, New York, beside anchor bridge 63,n.d. (Box 8:317)
    - Looking up at the underside of an anchor bridge,n.d. (Box 8:318)
    - Anchor bridge 61 on the Main Line with anchor bridge 211H on the Harlem River Branch next to it in New Rochelle Junction, New York,n.d. (Box 8:319)
    - One post of an anchor bridge including its supporting pier,n.d. (Box 8:320)
    - An anchor bridge and catenary over railroad tracks,n.d. (Box 8:321)
    - Land under construction beside railroad tracks,n.d. (Box 8:322)
    - Looking up at catenary wires,n.d. (Box 8:323)
    - A view from above of catenary, an anchor bridge, and New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad passenger train 352,n.d. (Box 8:324)
    - An anchor bridge at the end of a railroad station platform with four triangular catenary overhead,n.d. (Box 8:325)
    - A view from a railroad station platform looking down the tracks at an anchor brdige and catenary,n.d. (Box 8:326)
    - A pedestrian platform over a railraod track with catenary wires running beneath it,n.d. (Box 8:327)
    - Catenary running above a single track next to a railroad station platform,n.d. (Box 8:328)
    - A view down the tracks at a railroad station with two anchor bridges at either end of the platform and four triangular catenary overhead,n.d. (Box 8:329)
    - A view from the platform of a railroad station looking towards a town with triangular catenary overhead,n.d. (Box 8:330)
    - A different view from a railroad station platform towards a town with triangular catenary overhead and anchor bridges in the distance,n.d. (Box 8:331)
    - A view, possibly from a train in motion, of an anchor bridge next to some construction,n.d. (Box 8:332)
    - A view, possibly from a train in motion, of an anchor bridge in a rural setting,n.d. (Box 8:333)
    - An anchor bridge with A-frame posts,n.d. (Box 8:334)
    - A view of a railroad station platform with catenary wires running overhead and an anchor bridge near the end of the platform,n.d. (Box 8:335)
    - An off center view of a railroad station platform with catenary wires overhead,n.d. (Box 8:336)
    - An anchor bridge holding transformers next to a signal station,n.d. (Box 8:337)
    - An out of focus view of a railroad station with a train leaving the platform. An anchor bridge stands at the end of the platform and catenary wires run over the tracks,n.d. (Box 8:338)
    - An electric locomotive crossing a birdge with catenary wires overhead,n.d. (Box 8:339)
    - EF-1 class freight electric #109 with freight train, n.d. (Box 8:340)
    - EY-2 class electric switcher #222 (or possibly 226) with freight train, n.d. (Box 8:341)
    - A railroad station with triangular catenary overhead and anchor bridges across the tracks, n.d. (Box 8:342)
    - A view looking up an an anchor bridge and triangular catenary, n.d. (Box 8:343)
    - A junction between two sets of railroad tracks with an anchor bridge over each track. This image was probably taken at New Rochelle Junction, New York, with anchor bridges 61 on the Main Line on the right and 211H on the Harlem River Branch on the left. Two men walk on the tracks, n.d. (Box 8:344)
    - An anchor bridge with a tall wooden fence being built next to it,n.d. (Box 8:345)
    - An anchor bridge with transformers on it,n.d. (Box 8:346)
    - New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad electric locomotive 364 under an anchor bridge with a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad passenger train passing it on the rightn.d. (Box 8:347)
    - Cars parked near an area where a building is under construction by a railroad track with two anchor bridges in view,n.d. (Box 8:348)
    - Four men in a field next to a railroad track with four triangular catenary overhead and two anchor bridges in view,n.d. (Box 8:349)
    - A group of men working on a railroad track near a railroad bridge and an anchor bridge,n.d. (Box 8:350)
    - Construction of a building near a railroad track with many cars parked near the site,n.d. (Box 8:351)
    - Concrete supports at a construction site near a railroad track, possibly the construction of a thruway near New Rochelle Junction, New York,n.d. (Box 8:352)
    - Men working at a construction site next to a railroad track with an anchor bridge in view,n.d. (Box 8:353)
    - An anchor bridge with catenary wires,n.d. (Box 8:354)
    - A tall wooden fence being built next to an anchor bridge,n.d. (Box 8:355)
    - Looking up at an anchor bridge,n.d. (Box 8:356)
    - The back side of a tall wooden fence being built next to an anchor bridge,n.d. (Box 8:357)
    - An anchor bridge and catenary wires over railroad tracks,n.d. (Box 8:358)
    - A view down a single track with an anchor bridge and catenary wire overhead,n.d. (Box 8:359)
    - A close-up view of an anchor bridge over a single track,n.d. (Box 8:360)
    - An elecrtric locomotive moving towards an anchor bridge on a single track with catenary wires engaged with its pantograph,n.d. (Box 8:361)
    - A view down a single railroad track with a catenary wire overhead and anchor bridges in the distance,n.d. (Box 8:362)
    - A man walking towards an anchor bridge on a single railroad track with catenary overhead. Two men in the distance stand near a different railroad track,n.d. (Box 8:363)
    - A view of catenary over railroad tracks with anchor bridges in the distance,n.d. (Box 8:364)
    - A view of three railroad tracks with catenary overhead connecting to an anchor bridge,n.d. (Box 8:365)
    - A view of catenary over three railroad tracks with a group of men standing on a different set of tracks in the distance,n.d. (Box 8:366)
    - Catenary and an anchor bridge over railroad tracks in a rural setting,n.d. (Box 8:367)
    - An anchor bridge with A-frame posts over a group of three railroad tracks on the left and one track on the right,n.d. (Box 8:368)
    - Three railroad tracks with an anchor bridge overhead and two men standing to the left,n.d. (Box 8:369)
    - Three railroad tracks with an anchor bridge and catenary wires overhead,n.d. (Box 8:370)
    - A view of catenary running under a bridge with anchor bridges in the distance,n.d. (Box 8:371)
    - An electric New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad locomotive with its pantograph in contact with catenary about to travel under an anchor bridge,n.d. (Box 8:372)
    - Triangular catenary over four railroad tracks in a railroad station,n.d. (Box 8:373)
    - A view of an anchor bridge at a railroad station extending out over the platform and into the station parking lot,n.d. (Box 8:374)
    - [Note: Images 375 through 469 are varoius view of the right-of-way, catenary structures, wire train repairing damaged catenary, and wrecked locomotive and cars in the Bridgeport, Connecticut, area following the Federal wreck in July 1955]
    - A view of one of the Bridgeport, Connecticut railroad stations with an anchor bridge at the end of the platform,July 1955 (Box 9:375)
    - An anchor bridge in Bridgeport, Connecticut,July 1955 (Box 9:376)
    - Anchor bridges along the railroad tracks in Bridgeport, Connecticut,July 1955 (Box 9:377)
    - A passenger train at the platform of the Bridgeport, Connecticut, railroad station under an anchor bridge,July 1955 (Box 9:378)
    - A New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad electric locomotive behind another train at the platform of the Bridgeport, Connecticut, railroad station,July 1955 (Box 9:379)
    - A view of a wrecked New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad passenger car, July 1955 (Box 9:380)
    - A wrecked New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad passenger car on the ground between two sets of railroad tracks with a large group of people on the tracks to its right,July 1955 (Box 9:381)
    - A wrecked New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad car between two sets of railroad tracks with men standing near it on either end,n.d. (Box 9:382)
    - A close-up view of the underside of a wrecked New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad car with a group of men standing behind it,July 1955 (Box 9:383)
    - Another view of the underside of a wrecked New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad car,July 1955 (Box 9:384)
    - A wrecked railroad car next to an anchor bridge,July 1955 (Box 9:385)
    - Three wrecked New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad passenger cars with three men standing in front of them,July 1955 (Box 9:386)
    - A wrecked railroad car with a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad passenger car behind it,July 1955 (Box 9:387)
    - Several wrecked New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad cars,July 1955 (Box 9:388)
    - A pile of wrecked New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad cars near a small brick building with an anchor bridge in the background,July 1955 (Box 9:389)
    - Possibly a wrecked Pennsylvania Railroad passenger car on top of a concrete block,July 1955 (Box 9:390)
    - Possibly a wrecked Pennsylvania Railroad passenger car in a ditch along with several other wrecked railroad cars. Small brick buildings stand very near the wreck,July 1955 (Box 9:391)
    - The underside of a railroad car standing on a large concrete block,July 1955 (Box 9:392)
    - A wrecked passenger car with its underside showing,July 1955 (Box 9:393)
    - The roof of a wrecked New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad passenger car,July 1955 (Box 9:394)
    - Two men sitting and one man standing on railroad tracks with a group of people in the lot below them,July 1955 (Box 9:395)
    - Another view of two men sitting and one man standing on the railroad tracks with a group of people in the lot below them,July 1955 (Box 9:396)
    - Four men on the railroad tracks with a group of people in the lot behind them,July 1955 (Box 9:397)
    - An electric locomotive heading a long train with passenger and freight cars under several anchor bridges,July 1955 (Box 9:398)
    - The end of a wrecked railroad car resting on a concrete block and another car,July 1955 (Box 9:399)
    - A wrecked New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad locomotive turned on its side between two railroad tracks,July 1955 (Box 9:400)
    - A wrecked railroad car with a man behind it retrieving his shirt from its resting place on top of the wreckage, July 1955 (Box 9:401)